Wilder Salgado Lopez

.Net Developer

Linkedin wslwildersal@hotmail.com +57 318 311 2222



PROFILE

Information Systems Manager Graduated from the Nacional University of Manizales, Colombia, has 10 years of experience focused in .Net, using Scrum Framework as an agile methodology, Wilder has worked in projects for financial companies, airlines companies, manufacturing companies and among others.

Wilder has worked with technologies like .Net, .Net framework, .Net Core, C#, Sql Server, angular, Azure devops, Git, Selenium, Nunit, Specflow. Wilder currently is a Senior developer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

TECHNOLOGIES:

- .Net 6,7,8.
- .Net core.
- SQL Server, Reporting Services.
- Azure Environment.
- Angular, Angular Js.
- Git
- Entity Framework, Dapper.
- NUnit, Selenium, SpecFlow.

CERTIFICATIONS:

- Universidad Angular De Cero a Experto en Angular! Udemy.
- Programación Orientada a Objetos y principios SOLID Udemy.
- Getting started with DevOps using Azure DevOps & Docker Udemy.
- Patrones de diseño en C# Aplicados en ASP .Net Udemy.
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals Microsoft.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Perficient LatinAmerica Crushbank (Jul. 2021 -- Present)

.Net Developer

Developer of the new features request by the client. Fix applications error and maintenance of existing code

- Launch Budgeter feature in production as feature leader
- Launch classifier feature to production as developer
- Launch ranking results feature to production as feature leader

Globant Kantar, Ernst and Young (Mar. 2020 – Jul. 2021)

.Net Developer

Report migration from crystal reports to SSRS ETL process for a new product Help with the Implementation of Scrum framework to the team. Creation and maintain of the custom reports for Kantar Media application

Lead the team in the creation of custom reports for Kantar

NewShore Servicios Globales S.L. Vueling (Mar. 2019 – Mar. 2020)

.Net Developer Senior Team Leader and Tech Lead

Restructuring and creation of features for the booking process of the Vueling airline, support to the development team and planning teamwork during the sprints.

- Refactor and implement the new contact form
- Implement the new services form in manage your booking section

XpertGroup S.A.S Premex, Confiar, Nutresa (Apr. 2018 – Feb. 2019)

Semisenior Developer

provide support in development, development of solutions, having constant communication with customers and exercising activities development team leadership.

- Creation new concentrate formulation module for Premex
- Creation of module of pricing comparison for Nutresa using python
- Support portfolio module in Confiar

NewShore Servicios Globales S.L. Vueling (May. 2017 – Apr. 2018)

.Net Developer Semisenior

Restructuring and creation of features for the booking process of the Vueling airline, and training junior developers.

- Creation the new payment module
- Creation the new service to send post-purchase process emails

Hada S.A. Reporting (Mar. 2016 – Apr. 2017)

Analyst and Developer TIC

Software development activities that seek optimization and meet the needs of the information system for the continuous improvement of business group processes. Work under the environment Embarcadero of Delphi, with databases engine SQL Server and reports management Crystal Reports..

• Lead the new set of reports to have the history of changes in the formulation of the products

Alsus It Group S.A.S (Mar. 2014 – Oct. 2015)

Junior Software and development Engineer

Activities concerning the construction of web-based software, complemented with design and modelling based in certified processes of software engineering.

Start as .Net Developer

EDUCATION

National University of Colombia – Manizales INFORMATION SYSTEM MANAGEMENT (August 2013)